A Finding Aid to the Jean Davidson Papers, 1959-1995, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Jean Davidson papers
1959-1995
Archives of American Art
Davidson, Jean
AAA.davijean
Archival Resource Key
0.4 Linear feet
The scattered papers of painter Jean Davidson measure 0.4 linear feet and date from 1959 to 1995. Found are biographical material, correspondence, drawings, notes, photographs, and printed material. Also found is a video recording of an interview with Davidson conducted by David Howard.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Scope and Contents
The scattered papers of painter Jean Davidson measure 0.4 linear feet and date from 1959 to 1995. Found are biographical material, correspondence, drawings, notes, photographs, and printed material. Also found is a video recording of an interview with Davidson conducted by David Howard.
Biographical / Historical
Jean Davidson (1923-2003) was an abstract painter active in New York City and Woodstock, New York. She was known for her abstract minimalist paintings that used very pale color.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jean Davidson in 1996.
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the papers are arranged as one series.
Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Women artists; Women painters; Video recordings; Interviews
- Jean Davidson Papers, 1959-1995; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1, OVs 2-3
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials include a resume. Correspondence is with friends including De Hirsh Marqules. Drawings include pencil portraits and one color abstraction. Photographs depict Davidson in her studio and her artwork. Printed material includes clippings and exhibition announcements and catalogs. Also included is a VHS recording of an interview, entitled "Maximum Minimalism" with Jean Davidson conducted by David Howard.
  - Biographical Material, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Drawings, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drawings, Oversized, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 2)
  - Interview, 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes, 1977-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Oversized, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 3)
  - Printed Material, 1961-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7-9)